Guide to the Arthur H. and Mary Marden Dean Lafayette Collection, 1520-1973
Lafayette Collection (Arthur H. and Mary Marden Dean Lafayette Collection), 1520-1973
- Series VI. Polish Revolution
  - Labau, Conte de (Box 153, Folder 25)
    8 Mars 1831. Paris. 1l.
  - Laboullaye (Box 153, Folder 26)
    Général, Nous avons l'honneur de vous adresser 243f. 70c...
  - Lacoste, A. (Box 153, Folder 27)
    9 Mars 1831. Damazan. 1l.
  - Lafritte, J. (Box 153, Folder 28)
    March 18, [1831] Paris. 1l.
  - Lainserre (Box 153, Folder 29)
    28 Mars 1831. Vaucauleurs. 1l.
  - Lardhet (Box 153, Folder 30)
    17 Mars 1831. Pontiose. 1l.
  - Lareschef (Box 153, Folder 31)
    March 18, 1831. Paris. 1l.
  - Laroyenne (Box 153, Folder 32)
    24 Janvier 1831. St. Germain. 1l.
  - Lassailly (Box 153, Folder 33)
    28 Février 1831. Berguer. 1l.
    Mon Général, MM. les officiers...
  - Lassailly (Box 153, Folder 34)
    7 Mars 1831. Berguer. 1l.
  - Lasteyrie, C. de (Box 153, Folder 35)
    Je vous envoie... la lettre... du G. Dwernicki
  - Lasteyrie, C. de (Box 153, Folder 36)
    Je vous renvoie... la lettre que vous avés communiqué au Comité...
  - Lasteyrie, C. de (Box 153, Folder 37)
    20 Janvier 1831. Paris. 1l.
  - Leclerliowski, Jean (Box 153, Folder 38)
    13 Mars 1833. [Paris?] 1l.
  - Lelewel, Joachim (1786-1861) (Box 153, Folder 39)
    18 Mars 1833. Tours. 1l.
  - Lelewel, Joachim (1786-1861) (Box 153, Folder 40)
    14 Juillet 1833. Tours. 1l.
  - Lelewel, Joachim (1786-1861) (Box 153, Folder 41)
    29 Juillet 1833. Tours. 1l.
  - Lelewel, Joachim (1786-1861) (Box 153, Folder 42)
    29 Août 1833. Abbeville. 1l.
  - Lelewel, Joachim (1786-1861) (Box 153, Folder 43)
    8 Octobre 1833. Bruxelles. 1l.
  - Lelewel, Joachim (1786-1861) (Box 153, Folder 44)
    27 Novembre 1833. Bruxelles. 1l.
  - Lemaire (Box 153, Folder 45)
    21 Mars 1831. Hunique. 1l.
  - Lemoine (Box 153, Folder 46)
    [n. d.] Saint Gaultier. 1l.
  - [Levesques, ] (Box 153, Folder 47)
    21 Mars 1831. Lille. 1l.
  - La Loge Polonaise de La Fayette père des Peuples... (Box 153, Folder 48)
    Le quatrième jour du 1er mois, l'an de la V. L. 5833. 1l.
  - [Louet?], Alexandre (Box 153, Folder 49)
    1 Mars 1831. Brest. 1l.
    Monsieur et honorable...
  - [Louvet, Edouard]? (Box 153, Folder 50)
    September 1, 1826. 1l.
  - Mackniecki, Casimir (Box 154, Folder 1)
    October 22, 1831. Hambourg. 2 ll.
  - Magnan (Box 154, Folder 2)
    8 Mars 1831. Valence. 1l.
    Monsieur le Général...
  - Le Maire de la Comune de Cérisy-la-Fôret (Box 154, Folder 3)
    22 Septembre 1831. Cérisy-la-Fôret. 1l.
  - Le maire de la ville de Lapalisse (Box 154, Folder 4)
    12 Février 1831. Lapalisse. 1l.
  - Le maire de la ville de Nevers (Box 154, Folder 5)
    12 Septembre 1831. Nevers. 1l.
  - Le maire de la ville de Niort (Box 154, Folder 6)
    9 Septembre 1831. Niort. 1l.
  - Maison, W. (Box 154, Folder 7)
    20 Octobre 1831. Schönbrunn près Vienne. 3 ll.
  - Marczewski, Louis (Box 154, Folder 8)
    26 Février 1833. Paris. 1l.
  - [Mare ?] (Box 154, Folder 9)
    2 Septembre 1831. Niort. 1l.
  - Markowski, Jerôme (Box 154, Folder 10)
    December 15, 1863. Paris. 1l.
  - Martéal, Voltigeur de la Garde Nationale (Box 154, Folder 11)
    8 Mars 1831. Bourges. 1l.
  - Martéal (Box 154, Folder 12)
    14 Mars 1831. 1l.
  - Masclet, Amé-Thérèse-Joseph (1760-1833) (Box 154, Folder 13)
    6 Mars 1831. Nice. 1l. & accompanying document
  - Maugin (Box 154, Folder 14)
    15 Mars 1831. Le Puy. 1l.
  - Mélon (Box 154, Folder 15)
    22 Mars 1831. Auxere. 1l.
  - Menou, Baron de (Box 154, Folder 16)
    9 Avril 1842. Petit Charonne. 1l.
  - Menou, Baron de (Box 154, Folder 17)
    22 Mars 1843. Petit Charonne. 1l.
  - Menou, Baron de (Box 154, Folder 18)
    4 Août 1844. Petit Charonne. 1l.
  - Metzger (Box 154, Folder 19)
    December 18, 1830. Epernay. 2 ll.
  - Meyer (Box 154, Folder 20)
    8 Octobre 1831. Colmar. 1l.
  - Milhès (Box 154, Folder 21)
    10 Mars 1831. Besançon. 1l.
  - Ministère de l'Intérieur (Box 154, Folder 22)
    ALS to M. Royer-Collard
    10 Août 1841. Paris. 1l.
  - Ministère de la Guerre (Box 154, Folder 23)
    20 Avril 1832. Paris. 1l.
  - Moro (Box 154, Folder 24)
    March 4, 1832. Vienna. 2 ll.
  - Mourdan (Box 154, Folder 25)
    11 Mars 1831. Aiaccio. 1l.
  - Nanon (Box 154, Folder 26)
    14 Mars 1831. Phalsburg. 1l.
  - Nasse, Frédéric (Box 154, Folder 27)
    22 Février 1831. Lisieux. 1l.
  - [Nemaine, ]? (Box 154, Folder 28)
    22 Mars 1831. Paris. 1l.
  - Nicole (Box 154, Folder 29)
    10 Mars 1831. Dole. 1l.
  - Niemcewicz, Ursin (Box 154, Folder 30)
    September, 1831. Ursinow. 1l.
  - Niemojowski (Box 154, Folder 31)
    22 Décembre 1831. Paris. 2 ll.
  - Niemojowski (Box 154, Folder 32)
    December 27, 1831. Paris. 1l.
  - Noirpoudre (Box 154, Folder 33)
    20 Février 1831. Cult. 1l.
  - Noirpoudre (Box 154, Folder 34)
    18 Mars 1831. Cult près Marnay. 1l.
  - Notté, Pierre Claude and Helene Stubbs Notté (Box 154, Folder 35)
    [letter from their grandson included]
    10 Février 1832. 2 ll.
  - Nourry (Box 154, Folder 36)
    29 Mars 1831. au Puy. 1l.
  - Nylius (Box 154, Folder 37)
    ALS to [Comité Centrale en Faveur des Polonais]
    20 Janvier 1831. St. Omer. 1l.
  - Ostrowski, Antoine (Box 154, Folder 38)
    May 19, 183-? Paris. 1l.
  - Ostrowski, Antoine (Box 154, Folder 39)
    October 13, 1840. Versailles. 1l.
  - Ostrowski, Antoine (Box 154, Folder 40)
    October 17, 1831. Breslau. 1l.
  - Ostrowski, Antoine (Box 154, Folder 41)
    March 13, 1832. Dresde. 1l.
  - Ostrowski, Antoine (Box 154, Folder 42)
    April 23, 1832. Paris. 3 ll.
  - Ostrowski, Antoine (Box 154, Folder 43)
    30 Juin 1832. Paris. 1l.
  - Ostrowski, Antoine (Box 154, Folder 44)
    1 Juillet 1832. Paris. 1l.
  - Ostrowski, Antoine (Box 154, Folder 45)
    August 19, 1832. Paris. 1l.
  - Ostrowski, Antoine (Box 154, Folder 46)
    January 1, 1833. Paris. 1l.
  - Ostrowski, Antoine (Box 154, Folder 47)
    ALS to Monsieur de Lafayette [George Washington Lafayette]
    June 15, 1836. Versailles. 1l.
  - Ostrowski, Antoine (Box 154, Folder 48)
    August 3, 1836. Versailles. 1l.
  - Ostrowski, Antoine (Box 154, Folder 49)
    ALS to [George Washington Lafayette]?
    9 Février 1837. Versailles. 1l.
  - Ostrowski, Antoine (Box 154, Folder 50)
    February 12, 1837. Versailles. 1l.
  - Ostrowski, Antoine (Box 154, Folder 51)
    February 23, 1837. Versailles. 1l.
  - Ostrowski, Antoine (Box 154, Folder 52)
    15 Août 1837. Versailles. 1l.
  - Ostrowski, Antoine (Box 154, Folder 53)
    17 Février 1840. Versailles. 1l.
  - Ostrowski, Antoine (Box 154, Folder 54)
    19 Février 1842. Versailles. 1l.
  - Ostrowski, Antoine (Box 154, Folder 55)
    ALS to La Garde Nationale de Varsovie
    June 4, 1834. St. Germain-en-Laye. 1l.
  - Paris Garde Municipale (Box 155, Folder 1)
    7 Mars 1831. Paris. 1l.
  - Payne, Henry (Box 155, Folder 2)
    December 27, 1831. Nottingham. 1l.
  - Pertugé, N. (Box 155, Folder 3)
    12 Mars 1831. Les Sables d'Olonne. 1l.
  - Pinet, Emile (Box 155, Folder 4)
    5 Juin 1833. Bergerac. 1l.
  - Pinet, Emile (Box 155, Folder 5)
    7 Juin 1833. Bergerac. 2 ll.
  - Pol, General (Box 155, Folder 6)
    April 10, 1840. 1l.
  - Polish Committe Members (Box 155, Folder 7)
    ALS [...] to General Lafayette
    March 19, 1832. New York. 1l.
    A proposition has been made...
  - Les Polonais des diverses Provinces de Pologne et de Lithuanie, réunis à Paris en 1832 (Box 155, Folder 8)
    AL [copy] to Dwernicki, Ostrowski, and others
    1832. Paris. 1l.
  - Les Polonais residents dans la Département de l'Indre (Box 155, Folder 9)
    1 Mars 1833. 1l.
  - Potulicki, Comte (Box 155, Folder 10)
    19 Décembre 1831. Paris. 1l.
  - Preissac, L de (Box 155, Folder 11)
    19 Mars 1831. Plonigeau. 1l.
  - [Pussen, ] (Box 155, Folder 12)
    26 Février 1831. Lille. 1l.
  - [Pusy, ] (Box 155, Folder 13)
    4 Mars 1831. Lille. 1l.
  - 14e Régiment de Chasseurs à Cheval (Box 155, Folder 14)
    28 Février 1831. 2 ll.
  - La R. L. Française élue Ecossaise... (Box 155, Folder 15)
    le 6e jour du 2e mois de l'an de la V. L. 5831. Bordeaux. 1l.
  - Radziewski (Box 155, Folder 16)
    July 9, 1833. Paris. 1l.
  - Rajan (Box 155, Folder 17)
    16 Mars 1831. Rodez. 2 ll.
  - Ranc (Box 155, Folder 18)
    October 12, 1836. Paris. 1l.
  - Une réunion d'amis (Box 155, Folder 19)
    26 Février 1831. Villeneuve sur Lot. 1l.
  - Reynaud (Box 155, Folder 20)
    5 Février 1831. Gilhivers. 1l.
    Vénérable Général...
  - Reynaud (Box 155, Folder 21)
    14 Mars 1831. Puy. 1l.
  - Richard (Box 155, Folder 22)
    30 Mars 1831. Poitiers. 1l.
  - [Ridevnot]? (Box 155, Folder 23)
    9 Mars 1831. Calais. 1l.
  - Rigal (Box 155, Folder 24)
    9 Octobre 1831. Lons-le-Saunier. 2 ll.
  - Rimkiewicz, Joseph (Box 155, Folder 25)
    April 19, 1833. Naney. 1l.
  - Rivers (Box 155, Folder 26)
    February 25, 1832. Paris. 1l.
  - Rivier (Box 155, Folder 27)
    27 Février 1831. Grenoble. 1l.
  - Rivier (Box 155, Folder 28)
    18 Octobre 1831. Grenoble. 1l.
  - Robert (Box 155, Folder 29)
    19 Mars 1831. Yssengeaux. 1l.
  - Robin, B. David (Box 155, Folder 30)
    21 Février 1831. La Rochelle. 1l.
  - Roget, A. (Box 155, Folder 31)
    14 Mars 1831. St. Michel. 1l.
  - [Romeuf, ]? (Box 155, Folder 32)
    6 Mars 1831. Montmédy. 1l.
  - Romeuf (Box 155, Folder 33)
    14 Mars 1831. Montmédy. 1l.
  - Rosoy. Garde Nationale (Box 155, Folder 34)
    9 Mars 1831. Rosoy. 1l.
  - Rouselle, Fr. (Box 155, Folder 35)
    11 Mars 1831. Montmédy. 1l.
  - Rozycki, General Samuel (Box 155, Folder 36)
    AL (translation) to M. le Comte Ledochowski
    27 Février 1832. Brunn. 1l.
  - Rudolphe, maria (Box 155, Folder 37)
    April 11, 1833. Dôle. 1l.
  - [Saice?, A.] (Box 155, Folder 38)
    28 Février 1831. Dun sur Mense. 1l.
  - Salle, P. (Box 155, Folder 39)
    January 16, 1831. Rouen. 1l.
  - Sarent, Louis (Box 155, Folder 40)
    ALS to Sarent-Réal
    December 8, 1831. Lazaret d'Jobaselbach. 1l.
  - Sarent-Réal (Box 155, Folder 41)
    October 27 1831. Paris. 1l.
  - Scheibel (Box 155, Folder 42)
    2 Mars 1831. Thann. 2 ll.
  - Schlisler (Box 155, Folder 43)
    19 Avril 1831. Lyon. 1l.
    Si votre main vénérable...
  - Schöni, A... (Box 155, Folder 44)
    18 Septembre 1831. Bienne. 1l.
  - Selaidieraine (Box 155, Folder 45)
    21 Septembre 1831. Valognes. 1l.
  - Seminel, Auguste (Box 155, Folder 46)
    6 Mars 1831. Caen. 1l.
  - Seminel, Auguste (Box 155, Folder 47)
    11 Mars 1831. Caen. 1l.
  - Sérengue, Virginie (Box 155, Folder 48)
    11 Mars 1831. 1l.
  - Sidolkowicz (Box 155, Folder 49)
    October 8, 1832. Montpellier. 3 ll.
  - Skazynecky (Box 155, Folder 50)
    June 15, 1831. Praga. 1l.
  - Société du Cercle Littéraire de Tours (Box 156, Folder 1)
    February 27, 1831. Tours. 1l.
  - Société Lithuaniène (Box 156, Folder 2)
    February 12, 1832. Paris. 1l.
  - Soltyk, Roman (Box 156, Folder 3)
    [n. d., n. p.] 2 ll.
    Catastrophe de la Pologne...
  - Soltyk, Roman (Box 156, Folder 4)
    7 Décembre 1831. Paris. 1l.
  - Soltyk, Roman (Box 156, Folder 5)
    December 23, 1833. [Paris?] 1l.
  - Le Sous-Préfet de Cognac (Box 156, Folder 6)
    15 Mars 1831. Cognac. 1l.
  - Souterre, G. (Box 156, Folder 7)
    ALS to Victor de Tracy
    29 Mars 1831. Cambrai. 1l.
  - Tauzin le Jeune (Box 156, Folder 8)
  - Toulouzan (Box 156, Folder 9)
    23 Novembre 1831. Paris. 1l.
  - Tournière (Box 156, Folder 10)
    12 Mars 1831. Amiens. 1l.
  - Tournière (Box 156, Folder 11)
    23 Mars 1831. Amiens. 1l.
  - Trémeau, Fr. (Box 156, Folder 12)
    31 Mars 1831. 1l.
  - Underwood, John C. (Box 156, Folder 13)
    December 15, 1831. Clinton, NY. 1l.
    Honorary membership in Phi Gamma Alpha,
    Hamilton College.
  - Verdier-Latour (Box 156, Folder 14)
    6 Avril 1833. Clermont-Ferrand. 1l.
  - Vétellart, Marcelin (Box 156, Folder 15)
    13 Mars 1831. Le Mans. 1l.
  - Vilmette (Box 156, Folder 16)
    15 Mars 1831. Lunéville. 1l.
  - [Vournier, ]? (Box 156, Folder 17)
    12 Mars 1831. Paris. 1l.
  - [Vriel, ] (Box 156, Folder 18)
    11 Mars 1831. Altkirch. 1l.
  - Welles (Box 156, Folder 19)
    1831. Paris. 1l.
  - Willard, Emma Hart (1787-1870) (Box 156, Folder 20)
    April 5, 1832. Troy. 1l.
  - [Williams, Alphonse]? (Box 156, Folder 21)
    28 Septembre 1831. Alger. 1l.
  - [Winham, ]? (Box 156, Folder 22)
    20 Février 1831. Auxerre. 1l.
  - Wodzicki, Stanislas (Box 156, Folder 23)
    2 Janvier 1821. Cracovie. 5 ll.
  - Wolicki (Box 156, Folder 24)
    18 Mars 1831. Paris. 1l.
  - [Wurrd]? (Box 156, Folder 25)
    26 Février 1831. Boulogne. 1l.
    Mon général, J'écri...de vous envoyer le produit...
  - Yourangin, Amédée (Box 156, Folder 26)
    May 30, 1832. Issoudan. 1l.
  - Za..., Théophile (Box 156, Folder 27)
    23 [Juillet] 1833. La Rochelle. 1l.
  - Zaba (Box 156, Folder 28)
    December 7, 1831. 1l.
  - Zaleski, Constant (Box 156, Folder 29)
    February 15, 1832. Strasbourg. 1l.
  - Zaliwska (Box 156, Folder 30)
    10 Octobre 1833. 1l.
  - Zaliwski, Colonel Joseph (Box 156, Folder 31)
    September 26, 1832. Paris. 1l.
  - Zaliwski, Colonel Joseph (Box 156, Folder 32)
    5 Juin 1833. Gallicie. 1l.
  - Zanobin, P. de (Box 156, Folder 33)
    4 Mars 1831. Pernes. 1l.
  - Zeltner, Frantz de (Box 156, Folder 34)
    February 9, 1831. Paris. 1l.
  - Zeng, E. (Box 156, Folder 35)
    October 9, 1832. Paris. 1l.
  - Zenowicz, G. (Box 156, Folder 36)
    April 8, 1834. Paris. 1l.
  - Zenowicz, G. (Box 156, Folder 37)
  - Zimmer (Box 156, Folder 38)
    11 Mars 1831. Sedan. 1l.
    Mon Général, J'ai l'honneur de vous adresser...
- Series VII. Ephemera: prints, broadsides and memorabilia
  - Commemorative mug (Box 157)
    [Lafayette's 1824 American Tour. Bears likenesses of George Washington and Lafayette and the inscription "Republicans are
    not always ungrateful"]
    Richard Hall and Sons. n.d.
  - Commemorative medals. Transferred in Box 186 (Box 158)
    Empty.
  - Lafayette, Marquise de (Box 159, Folder 1)
    ALS (photostat) to King of Prussia
    December 3, 1792 Chavaniac
  - Lafayette (Box 159, Folder 2)
    L [typed transcription, to Samuel Morse]
    La Grange n.d.
  - Jeffrey Wyatt (?) (Box 159, Folder 3)
    ALS to Mme de Lafayette
    [concerning upkeep of estate]
    Jan 16, 1817 London
  - Frederick List (Box 159, Folder 4)
    ALS to Lafayette. [requests info. on French trade
    and economy]
    November 29, 1827(?) Reading, PA.
  - Petitions, 1825, 1829 (Box 159, Folder 5-6)
  - Lafayette. Portrait. (Box 159, Folder 7)
    [framed photograph 1 3/8 x 1 5/8, from
    painting by Ary Scheffer] n.d.
  - Lafayette. Portrait. (Box 159, Folder 8)
    [Life mask - photograph of the original study
    by Jean-Antoine Houdon (1741-1828) for statue
    commissioned by the Virginia Assembly]
    1785 1l.
  - Ayen, Jean Paul François de Noailles, duc d' (Box 159, Folder 9)
    Portrait [photographic negative and print]
    n.d. 1l.
  - Lafayette. (Box 159, Folder 10)
    Printed invitation to ball.
    Milan. n.d.
  - Lafayette. (Box 159, Folder 11)
    Obituary Ribbon.
    31 July, 1834. Allentown, PA.
  - Program to inaugural NYC gala, 2014 (Box 159, Folder 13)
  - C. Hadley Smith's program and photos of exhibition opening - the Arthur H. and Mary Marden Dean Lafayette Collection, 1964-04-06 (Box 159, Folder 14)
    Includes photos of President Perkins, Morris Bishop and Arthur Dean
  - Lafayette. (Box 159)
    Ribbon. "The Nation's Guest." [1824?]
  - Federation fan, with an allegorical scene inspired by La Fontaine (left), Louis XVI, La Fayette and Bailly (center) and representatives of the three estates (right) (Box 160)
  - Lafayette Fan (Box 161)
    [painted wood with openwork. One side depicts
    le Dauphin Louis XVII, Marie-Antoinette
    and the storming of the Bastille; the other, Louis
    XVI, Lafayette and an allegorical figure of the
    Revolution]
  - Silk items (purse and ribbons) (Box 161)
  - Small ceramic cup (Box 162)
    [Verre en opaline: "La Nation, La Loi, le Roi"]
  - Plaque of Lafayette (Box 162)
    Bronze with wood frame
  - Destutt de Tracy, Antoine Louis Claude (Box 162)
    Bronze medallion by David D'Angers
  - Letter from President Eisenhower to M. E. Baiter thanking him and "Committee of France-American Friendship, Washington-Lafayette" for bronze medal, 1957 (Box 191)
    Framed with portrait
  - Sprig of cypress plucked at Washington's grave, October 17, 1824; MU-2269 (Box 192)
  - Limoges bone china plates, decorated with scenes of Lafayette's participation in the American Revolution, 1973
- Series VIII. Prints and Graphics
  - Portrait of La Fayette in the uniform of the National Guard., n.d.; 1 (Box 163)
    Lithograph by J. Rigo. Paris, P. Amic l'Aînè, 127mm. x 194mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in the uniform of the National Guard., n.d.; 2 (Box 163)
    Anonymous print. 104mm. x 154mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in the uniform of the National Guard. Inscription: "Marie-Paul-Josh.-Yves Mottier, Mquis. De La Fayette, Lieutentant-Gal., Commandant en Chef l'Armée Du Centre, 1791. Général en Chef Des Gardes N.ales De France, 1830.", 4 (Box 163)
    Engraving by Morinet after a drawing by Pol Justus and a painting by Larivière. [Paris], [1838] 120mm. x 182mm. See Blancheteau #331.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform., n.d.; 5 (Box 163)
    Lithograph by Engelmann. Inscription: "Général Lafayette, défenseur des liberté." 90mm. x 130mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform, holding the declaration: "La Garde Nationale 1830.", n.d.; 6 (Box 163)
    Print [lithograph by Bénard?] after a painting by A. Menut. 110mm. x 146m. See also Blancheteau #502
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform., n.d.; 7 (Box 163)
    Anonymous print. 49mm. diameter
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform., August 26, 1785; 8 (Box 163)
    Engraving by [William] Angus. London, I. Fielding, 95mm. x 150mm See also Blancheteau #88
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform., n.d.; 9 (Box 163)
    Anonymous print. Inscription: "M. Le Marquis De La Fayette. Député de la Sénéch. de Riom en Auvergne. Elu par acclamation, Command. Général de la Garde National Parisienne." Paris, 95mm. x 150mm See also Blancheteau #88.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform., n.d.; 10 (Box 163)
    Anonymous print. Inscription: "Mr. le Marquis de la Fayette, Commandant General de la Garde Nationale Parisienne." (sic). 80mm. x 134mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in the uniform of the National Guard., n.d.; 11 (Box 163)
    Anonymous print. Oval, 55mm. x 78mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in the uniform of the National Guard, n.d.; 12 (Box 163)
    Engraved by T. Clarke. Philadelphia, Oval, 85mm. x 109mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in the uniform of the National Guard, titled: "La Fayette.", 1796; 13 (Box 163)
    Anonymous print F. Bolt, Oval, 59mm. x 68mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in the uniform of the National Guard., n.d.; 14 (Box 163)
    Anonymous print. Inscription: "Mr. La Marquis de la Fayette, Command.t Génér.l de la Gard Nation.le Parisienne." 80mm. x 60m.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in the uniform of the National Guard., n.d.; 15 (Box 163)
    Engraving by M. d. Sillieth. Inscription: "De la Fayete (sic). Commandant der Nationaale Garde." 90mm. x 157m.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform. Titled: "Marquis de la Fayette, n.d.; 16 (Box 163)
    Engraving by B. le Clair, after a drawing by L. Barre. 77mm. x 100m.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in the uniform of the National Guard., n.d.; 17 (Box 163)
    Engraving by Duchemin after a drawing by François Bonneville. Inscription: "Gilbert, Mottier, la Fayette. Député D'Auvergne a l'Assemblé Nat.le en 1789. Commandant Général de la Gde Parisienne." Paris, [1796?] oval, 82mm. x 102m. See Blancheteau #183.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in the uniform of the National Guard., n.d.; 18 (Box 163)
    Engraving by Fiesinger after a drawing by J. Guérin. Inscription: "Marie, Paul, Joseph, Roch, Yves, Gilbert de Mottier de la Fayette. Député D'Auvergne a l'Assemblée Nationale en 1789. Elu Commandant Général de la Garde Nationale Parisienne le 15 Juillet." Paris, [1789?] oval, 74mm. x 87m. See also Blancheteau #174.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in the uniform of the National Guard., 19 (Box 163)
    Engraving by Fiesinger after a drawing by J. Guérin. Copy of 163-18.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform, titled: "M. de La Fayette.", 1791; 20 (Box 163)
    Lithograph by Anker Smith. C. Forster. 79mm. x 92mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform., n.d.; 21 (Box 163)
    Anonymous print. Inscription: "Mr. de la Fayette, Com.dant Genéral de la Garde Nationale Parisienne." 60mm. x 78mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform., n.d.; 22 (Box 163)
    Anonymous print. Inscription: "La Fayette." 102mm. x 153mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform, titled: "La Fayette.", n.d.; 23 (Box 163)
    Engraving by Hopwood. Paris, Furne, 90mm. x 95mm. See also # 168-5.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform, titled: "Lafayette.", n.d.; 24 (Box 163)
    Engraving by Ethiou. Paris, Furner, 85mm. x 88mm. See also # 168-6.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform., n.d.; 25 (Box 163)
    Engraving by H.B. Hall & Sons. Inscribed autograph: "Lafayette." New York, 88mm. x 95mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in the uniform of the National Guard, titled: "Lafayette.", n.d.; 26 (Box 163)
    Anonymous print. Paris, P. Dien, 85mm. x 88m.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in the uniform of the National Guard., n.d.; 27 (Box 163)
    Lithograph by Delpech. 85mm. x 85mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in the uniform of the National Guard, titled: "Gen'l Lafayette.", n.d.; 28 (Box 163)
    Anonymous print. 52mm. x 78m.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform, titled: "Lafayette.", n.d.; 29 (Box 163)
    Engraving by [Charles-Aimé] Forestier. 76mm. x 92mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform, titled: "Lafayette.", n.d.; 30 (Box 163)
    Anonymous print. oval, 68mm. x 76mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform, titled: "LaFayette.", n.d.; 31 (Box 163)
    Engraving by Porlier. Paris, 93mm. x 103m.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in the uniform of the National Guard, n.d.; 32 (Box 163)
    Anonymous lithograph. Paris, Formentin, 115mm. x 165mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform., n.d.; 33 (Box 163)
    Engraving by Al[exandre] Massard. Paris, 122mm. x 172mm. See Blancheteau # 526.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in the uniform of the National Guard., 1833; 34 (Box 163)
    Engraving by [Handivillier?] Blaisot. 72mm. x 75mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform., 35 (Box 163)
    Anonymous print. Inscription: "Marquis de Lafayette. General der Pariser Nationalgarde. [g.ldi.?] Sept. 17.57 Chavagnac im Dep. Der Obern [Loir?] 148mm. x 153mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in civilian clothes., 1 (Box 164)
    Anonymous print. Inscription: "General Lafayette, the friend of Liberty." 80mm. diameter
  - Portrait of La Fayette in civilian clothes., 2 (Box 164)
    Anonymous print. Copy of 164-1, without inscription. 80mm. Diameter
  - Portrait of La Fayette in civilian clothes, titled: "Le G.al Lafayette.", n.d.; 3 (Box 164)
    Anonymous print. Signed: "C.L.S." 165mm. x 195mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in uniform, titled: "Lafayette.", n.d.; 4 (Box 164)
    Lithograph by Kauffmann. 220mm. x 230mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in the uniform of the National Guard., n.d.; 5 (Box 164)
    Lithograph by Fuher. Paris, Lemercier, 140mm x 180mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in civilian clothes., 6 (Box 164)
    Engraving by J.-M. Fontaine after a painting by A. Scheffer. Engraved decorative border by Clerget. Paris, [1850? See Blancheteau #458] 65mm x 100mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in civilian clothes., n.d.; 7 (Box 164)
    Etching by H.B. Hall after a painting by A. Scheffer. 127mm x 185mm.
  - Portrait of La Fayette in civilian clothes, titled: "Lafayette."., n.d.; 8 (Box 164)
    Anonymous engraving. Signed: "C.G. Childs sc. on Steel." 130mm x 175mm.